<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on Ahmed Alghali Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:52168/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Ahmed Alghali Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 23:15:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:52168/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Where You Are Allowed To Be You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52168/posts/where_you_are_allowed_to_be_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 23:15:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:52168/posts/where_you_are_allowed_to_be_you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To nerd out and talk about a particular topic that you are deeply interested in/ obsessed with, requires you to unveil part of yourself. Your personality, your affection, your love for that topic. Often, it feels like dancing in the symphony of that subject(my analogy is very consumed, but I feel it holds true here).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While jumping between discussions on &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;substack.com&#34;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, I found myself watching this Kurt Vonnegut lecture.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GOGru_4z1Vc?si=RCY3DkrlbOj7We_e&#34;&gt;Watch the lecture&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of the Regret Minimization Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52168/posts/the_limits_of_the_regret_minimization_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:30:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:52168/posts/the_limits_of_the_regret_minimization_framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When making decisions in life, especially when we are faced with selecting between two events, we find ourselves comparing how important they are in order to determine which event we should choose. Some people study the implications of each decision and measure how rewarding or penalizing the outcomes might be. Picking the least penalty is a tactic for choosing a decision under this scenario.&#xA;I first  ago in one of Jeff Bezos’s interviews. he called it the &lt;em&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/jwG_qR6XmDQ?si=A_cH7C8Bqqwh94Zc&#34;&gt;Regret Minimization Framework.&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude Register</title>
      <link>http://localhost:52168/posts/gratitude_register/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:52168/posts/gratitude_register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone is atheist until the plane starts falling.&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;I have no clue who said this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The numerous different stories that act as catalysts for returning to God and thinking about the existence of a grand designer or creator, shared by people across the globe, are interesting. There are a variety of patterns, and often the most interesting ones are those concluded through epistemic rationality rather than convenience or bias—where there was evidence that God existed, for them.&#xA;One pattern is how God existed in everyday life. A good example is the historical belief that the creation of all temples and religions around the world throughout history is an innate, lowkey, subtle need for God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
