<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on Ahmed Alghali Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Ahmed Alghali Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consenting to the Game Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consenting_to_the_game_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consenting_to_the_game_rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This piece of writing was part of an article I’m writing, about how I would help someone answering the question of “what do I want to do”, where I discuss how to pick a major and what helps you to define the way you contribute to this world. I found the draft of the article to be very lengthy, I may expected the reader to be aware of difference notions upfront, so I preferred this topic to be referenced here. As many of my drafts are pointing to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Feel Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learning_to_feel_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learning_to_feel_again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think it&amp;rsquo;s important for people to present themselves as they are, which is messy, because to present yourself as perfect sets up an unfair standard for other people to live by.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;— Simon Sinek&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elaborate: Adding New Friends System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/elaborate_on_adding_new_friends_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:40:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/elaborate_on_adding_new_friends_system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You don’t know about real loss, because that only occurs when you love something more than you love yourself. I doubt you’ve ever dared to love anybody that much.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Sean, Good Will Hunting (Park Bench Scene)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although my previous blog post was expected to be an explanation of what I assumed to be something I adopted a long time ago and never updated before:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but I have never revised the list since a while&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding new friends system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/adding_new_friends_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/adding_new_friends_system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get asked:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you deal with ordinary people? The ones that don&amp;rsquo;t bother you? and when does it start that they enter your life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This question has got me thinking. I recalled that checklist (set of rules) I have for making new friends, but I have never revised the list for a while. I have seen cases where people just hack the system, and suddenly they are knocking on the door of my heart before even check-listing half of it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The set of rules I have adapted is simple enough to help me make new friends; however, it does a greater job preventing “bad friends.” It makes sure I can still enjoy life and have good healthy relationships (without the need to call them friends), and this is where it helps me the most. More about it later; first, let’s get to see where this starts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where You Are Allowed To Be You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_you_are_allowed_to_be_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 23:15:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/where_you_are_allowed_to_be_you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To nerd out and talk about a particular topic that you are deeply interested in/ obsessed with, requires you to unveil part of yourself. Your personality, your affection, your love for that topic. Often, it feels like dancing in the symphony of that subject(my analogy is very consumed, but I feel it holds true here).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of the Regret Minimization Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_limits_of_the_regret_minimization_framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:30:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_limits_of_the_regret_minimization_framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When making decisions in life, especially when we are faced with selecting between two events, we find ourselves comparing how important they are in order to determine which event we should choose. Some people study the implications of each decision and measure how rewarding or penalizing the outcomes might be. Picking the least penalty is a tactic for choosing a decision under this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude Register</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gratitude_register/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>ahmed@offsechq.com (A.Alghali)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gratitude_register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone is atheist until the plane starts falling.&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;I have no clue who said this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The numerous different stories that act as catalysts for returning to God and thinking about the existence of a grand designer or creator, shared by people across the globe, are interesting. There are a variety of patterns, and often the most interesting ones are those concluded through epistemic rationality rather than convenience or bias—where there was evidence that God existed, for them.&#xA;One pattern is how God existed in everyday life. A good example is the historical belief that the creation of all temples and religions around the world throughout history is an innate, lowkey, subtle need for God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
